It's 6 PM
and it's the I now call the January 5th,
2026 meeting of the city of Cheyenne
Planning Commission to order. Could we
have roll call, please?
>> Tony Leard
>> here.
>> Amy Hernandez,
>> present.
>> Bob Mataya
>> here.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
Boyd Wigum
>> present.
>> Lonnie Olsen
>> here.
>> Megan Connor
>> present remotely.
>> Mr. Chair, one member is absent. We do
have a quorum.
>> Okay.
>> We right now have a election of officers
to do.
First one is for election of chair.
I would be willing to
assume the chair again if everybody else
is in in agreement.
If there's anybody else who wants to
serve, I'd be happy to hear from them.
Mr. Chair, I I would nominate Boyd
Wigan.
All right.
Uh chair, I would second that.
Okay, let's should we have the other
voting?
>> Yeah.
And chair, you may vote unless you want
to call for any other nominations.
>> Is there any other nominations?
Okay,
let's have roll call, please.
Okay. The motion is for Boyd Wigum to be
the planning commission chair for 2026.
And now we're calling for um votes on
that.
>> Don't forget discussion.
>> Pardon me.
>> Chair, members of the of the commission,
uh don't forget discussion because we
should give Mr. Wigum any opportunity to
say yes or no.
>> Oh, okay.
I am willing to serve.
>> Okay.
Mr. Chair, would you like roll call or
just all those in favor?
>> All those in favor of of uh Mr.
>> Wigs
being the chair.
>> I
post.
>> Did we all say was it unanimous? Okay.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> All right. That motion passes. Boydwig
will be the chair for 2026.
>> Um, we can move uh to Boydwigum chairing
the meeting immediately or after the
election of officers is complete.
>> I was just going to nominate Tony Blair
to serve as vice chair at this point.
>> I second that.
>> And I would be willing to do that.
All those in favor say I.
>> I.
>> Appears to be unanimous.
>> Motion passes.
>> Okay. Now we have the the the position
of secretary.
I would like to nominate Robert MFA to
serve as secretary if he's willing.
>> Yeah, I would be willing.
All those in favor?
>> We have a second.
>> Is there Is there a a second?
>> I'd second that. Okay.
>> Is there anyone else wishing to make a
nomination?
>> If not, and Miss Connor, would you like
to also be nominated?
I um support Bob Mia's nomination.
>> Thank you.
>> All those in favor say I for this
nomination.
>> I I
>> I
>> Okay,
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> All righty.
>> With that, we will
>> it's your meeting now.
>> Do we need to shuffle now? I
>> you guys can stay in the same seats if
you'd like. I think it's good enough for
today.
>> Sure.
>> Give me the the hammer.
>> Okay. Um moving on to the next item of
business. Uh approval of agenda and
minutes um for the meeting of December
1st, 2025.
Do I have a motion? Chair or? No, I
guess we have to do the or are there any
modifications to to the agenda?
Hearing none.
Do I hear a motion on approval of
minutes of the December 1st, 2025
meeting?
>> Okay,
>> second.
>> Okay, it's been moved by Robert Ma,
seconded by Lonnie Olsen. Um,
any discussion? Any amend amendments,
changes, corrections to the minutes, the
draft minutes
hearing? None. Does this require a a
roll call?
>> Usually for minutes, we just do all in
favor.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. Well, then all in
favor of approval of the minutes as
drafted, please say I. I. I.
>> Opposed, please say nay.
>> Motion carries. Minutes are approved.
Uh, next item of of business is
disclosures, conflicts of interest for
any of the items appearing on the agenda
among the board. Hearing none,
uh, staff, would you please read item A
into the record? Item A, PUDC-25-250,
Cheyenne Business Parkway 15th filing
expedited plat
is do we have
>> agent
>> the agent here?
>> Good afternoon, chairman, members of the
planning commission. Casey Palma, Palma
land planning agent for the owner and
applicant.
Um, so what you have before you this
evening is a request for an expedited
plat. Um, this is to facilitate a
relocation of Floyd's truck service and
sales uh from their current location on
Second Street uh to the Campill Road
frontage. Uh because of the size of the
property, it's it's much bigger than um
what they need for their facility. uh
they're subdividing the remainder of the
property to be developed by others. Um
they'll be building the the roadway you
see on the preliminary plat map and then
occupying lot one as shown on the plat.
Um I think we've we've worked
extensively with staff over the last few
months. Uh some most of the delays on
our side not theirs. I would not they've
been excellent to work with on this.
There are a lot of uh things we had to
work through to to make this work. uh
both from the city's perspective and my
client's perspective and I think we've
worked through it all sufficiently and
really really pleased with uh with city
staff in working through this. Um
there's you know as noted in the staff
report the lot one for uh the proposed
truck sales and service facility uh
common lot two will be a pond sized to
accommodate the stormwater detention for
the entire property uh including the the
four lots plus the Floyd's facility
which as you can imagine has a lot of
pavement on it. Um
and I I think we you know we agree with
everything the SE port. I think it's
pretty clearly eligible for expedited. I
think we've worked through any of the
outstanding issues and would hope that
you'd be feel it uh suitable to advance
the final plat to the governing body and
I'd be happy to address any questions
you might have.
Okay.
>> Thank you. Any questions for the agent
uh from the board
from the commission?
Mr. Chairman, through you. Uh, I have
one question on you talk about there's I
think lot two is for drainage and it's
going to be maintained by the other five
lot owners. Is that going to be written
into their deeds or anything to make
sure the maintenance is taken care of?
>> Yeah, chair through you. Um, it is noted
on the face of the plat um that that lot
will be owned by undivided interest by
all the other owners. So it won't be
owned by one single uh person or entity
and um and then also stated that
maintenance will be um you know by the
owners in the plat. Additionally, there
will be a set of covenants and
restrictions filed with against the
property prior to any sales that that
stipulates what those um costs and
responsibilities are for maintenance.
Okay.
>> Any other questions?
questions from Zoomland.
Okay. Um, if if this is going to be
opened as undivided owned as undivided
interest, will there be an HOA or
anything like that that will be able to
contract with whoever is doing the
maintenance?
>> Um, yeah, a commercial version of an
HOA, commercial owners association. Um
and they'll hire they also because of
the location um this is a a pretty
substantial amount of roadway for the
city of Cheyenne to take on. Um they
have assured us that it will be on the
list for plowing and maintenance. But
you know given the location and the the
low number of people that it serves um
the COA's planning and and has talked
with the the city public works and
engineering departments about performing
that maintenance under the COA. So, if
there's a big snowstorm, they they'll
they'll be going out to plow that road
themselves. Um, the road's currently
proposed to be entirely concrete. So,
maintenance- wise, um, it should be less
of a burden on on the city, uh, as a
public roadway to have it be all
concrete. Um,
does that answer your question?
>> Anything else?
Okay. Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, members of the planning
commission, my name is Seth Lloyd. I
will be running the staff report for
Connor White today. Um, this project is
a expedited plat or request for an
expedited plat um to divide some land in
an industrial park um into multiple
lots. The area is currently um
designated as industrial on the future
land use map and has the zoning of HIV
industrial in the city.
Um the proposed plat is compatible with
both of these designations. The proposal
is to develop the land for industrial
purposes. The lots proposed are
buildable lots in this um zone district
and in this area with the exception of
lot two which is reserved for um
detention. Um lot two it's our
understanding will be maintained by has
a defined maintenance program um to be
maintained by the property owners within
the subdivision.
Um the
proposed Florence Way um is a public
street not truly required by uh the city
at this location. Um due to the freeway
and the industrial nature of the area,
there isn't really a required block size
um scenario. However, Florence Way would
provide more connectivity if the lot to
the west chooses to develop. And in the
interim, we'll have a temporary
culde-sac. Um open space is not required
in industrial development. Um so there's
not really a proposal on that end. Um
there's no phasing proposed with the
project. Um the project was reviewed for
engineering study compliance and there's
no issues at the plat level um
identified for engineering purposes. Um
there are a few technical corrections
that need to be made but generally
speaking um the plat satisfies all the
review criteria according to staff's
analysis. Um staff recommends approval
of this plat and approve recommends um
that it be expedited and I'm available
for any questions.
>> Commissioners questions for staff.
>> Mr. Chair through you.
>> Mr.
This is more of a probably a timing
logistical thing, not completely
relevant to our approval, I suppose, but
um so initially it sounds like it's just
that lot one of block one that's going
to be developed as a business and then
the other lots will eventually be sold
and developed. Um
and so I assume once that work begins on
lot one, at least the detention pond
would have to be constructed. Would they
have to will they construct or have to
construct that entire new road that kind
of goes on their backside and serves all
the other lots? I don't know if if lot
one's going to be served from there too
or just mostly from camp stool or some
of both.
>> Mr. Chair, um as a point of
clarification with this project, um the
proposed development is going to go on
lot one block two which is south of
Florence Way. So they will need Florence
Way in order to access their
development. And so they will be
proposing to develop Florence Way fully
with the initial development project.
>> Okay, I missed that. I was
>> there are two lot ones and we only had
said lot one previously. Oh, okay.
Any other questions?
With that, we'll move to public comment.
Anybody from public? Anybody on
Zoomland? Going once. going twice.
Public comment is closed.
Um,
commissioners,
I think I'd like to have a motion on the
table and then we can discuss discuss
motions.
Well, actually, is there
unless there's somebody that wants some
help on framing an emotion?
I like debates on a on a motion on the
on the table. So,
>> we have a
>> do we have a motion to work with?
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Commissioner Lar,
>> I I move to approve the Cheyenne
Business Parkway 15th filing preliminary
plat advancing the final plat to the
governing body with staff's recommended
condition.
>> Okay, we have a motion. Do I have a
second? Second. Seconded by Commissioner
Ma.
Do we have debate on the motion now that
we have a motion to debate or discuss?
There are questions to questions to
anybody to clarify before voting.
Hearing none, please please call roll.
Megan Connor,
>> yes.
>> Amy Hernandez,
>> hi.
>> Tony Leard,
>> hi. Lonnie Olsen.
>> Hi,
>> Bob Mataya.
>> I,
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you. Staff, please read item B
into the record.
>> Item B, PUDC-25-254,
Dry Creek Vista's preliminary plat.
>> Do we have an agent?
Good afternoon, chairman, members of the
planning commission, Casey Palma, Palma
land planning agent for the owner and
applicant.
Um, the item before you this evening is
owned by a single entity. Um, and it's a
little less cut and dry than the one we
previously discussed. Uh, this land and
these roadways have been platted and
replatted and vacated in different
fashions. um over about the last 50
years. There's some remainders of rights
of way. There's some rights of way that
have been vacated um back by the
commissioners in the 80s. And so, in
large part, this application was
intended to just clean up some of those
boundaries and define, you know, some of
the the uh
conflicts between different uh
previously recorded documents. And um
initially we had submitted this as well
as an expedited preliminary final plat
um and but we're we're amendable to
staff's recommendation to just divide
this out and hear this as a preliminary
plat only. Um there are two neighbors
affected by the Frank Court rightway
vacation. Um and a couple questions
still I think outstanding at at the
county just on research and kind of
backing everything up and and clarifying
the status of different things. Um BOPU
does have uh water and sewer main stubs
out of Rock Springs into Frank Court. So
that's another complicating issue. So uh
we're amendable to slowing it down a
little bit and kind of sorting through
all of those uh idiosyncrasies and then
coming in with a nice clean final plat
that everybody's on board with. Um and
likewise we're amendable to staff
conditions um
to uh provide a a independent vacation
map that can be um run through separate
from the plat. Uh it's been a little bit
challenging to coordinate plat
signatures with um with those adjacent
owners. So I think that that approach is
is acceptable to my client. Um, and then
there was a a couple small changes to
the final plat which in fact we've
already made sort of in in preparation
of this condition coming through. So
we're amendable to the conditions and
I'd be happy to address any questions
you might have
commissioners questions for the Asian
Mr. Chair through you uh commissioner
and turn on your
>> sorry I have a question on the two
residences. What are their lot sizes?
>> Um,
>> I had a little trouble reading the map.
>> Me, too.
>> They look like about 25 or 20 20,000 or
5,000 square feet.
>> Yeah. You mean the ones where the
residences are? I think they're maybe a
little bit smaller than that. Give me
one moment here, Commissioner. Uh, lot
one is 26,789.
That's the one at the north end there.
and that's that's pretty much already
established as a a separate residential
parcel.
>> Um, and then the down in the southeast
corner is uh existing residence, but
there are no sort of defining lines
around it and that's proposed at just
over 20,000 square feet. So, you were
pretty close on.
>> And what is going into lot what is it?
Lot three the big
>> um so nothing for now. I think the idea
was, like I said, mostly just to kind of
clean up these rights of way and put
those houses on sort of a conforming lot
that was defined by something other than
a deed description or
>> they're both on so they're both on
septic and well, right?
>> Um the southeast corner is connected to
the public BPU system. Um it is
>> Yep. The one at the north end is
currently on on well and septic. uh and
we have looked at a couple different
options for providing sewer and water to
that but at such time that the septic
fails. Um and also in the case that lot
three develops. So um there's no no
proposal to develop that now and nobody
you know wanting to buy it but um we've
looked at at how it could be developed
and how would the water and sewer run to
make sure that everybody had appropriate
services. is the one that's not
connected yet. Is it is the size of the
lot sufficient to meet the whatever the
code is for
>> for well and septic?
>> It's not the entire property is not
enough for the single well and septic.
So um
>> so it will have to have
>> it will have to have water and sewer
services at some point and uh we've
talked with BOPU about the different
options um sort of long services or
providing you know shorter mains than
with services coming off of them. So,
there's a few ways to do it, but until
uh you until something else kind of
comes to light, um I don't think those
would be like for instance the septic
failing or development on lot three. Um
there's no plans to do anything
immediately.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Mhm.
Any other commissioners have any
questions?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. So, are you
getting some negative feedback from the
adjacent homeowners regarding vacating
Frank?
>> Um, we haven't had any negative
feedback. We've just um had trouble
getting a hold of that the the small lot
owner there right adjacent to the
intersection of Frank Court and Rock
Springs. Um, I've actually taken a
couple trips to his house and we've sent
a letter. I don't have any phone number
email for them. Um, and so we just it's
just been hard to just find somebody to
talk to about it. Um the larger lot, you
know, beyond that and and the majority
of the frontage there is a large uh
basically apartment complex or patio
home development. Um and we we've had a
couple conversations with them, but
they're not opposed to it. It just
there's just sort of a lot of layers to
go through their registered agent and
forward it to them and um they didn't
seem to care much one way or the other.
I think their thought was if Frank Court
is vacated, we'll just expand our yards
in the in the back and make them bigger.
So, I I don't think they have any
concerns. Um, and I I don't think, you
know, the owner there at the corner um
isn't terribly negatively impacted. I
mean, it didn't doesn't really change
where he accesses his house from. Um,
there are a few improvements that fall
out into that rightway. So, vacing it
for him probably would be um a good
thing because now he doesn't have
improvements that are out in the
rightway. But
um nothing negative from anybody. So
>> yeah, it didn't seem like you had any
comments or any public.
>> Yeah, I don't think so.
>> Any other questions from the
commissioner?
>> Mr. Chair, through you,
>> Commissioner Lar. So just explain to us
briefly what what does happen if this
roadway is uh
vacated both that north south portion
and then I guess there's some confusion
or this uh about the east west part that
kind of goes between lot three and lot
one and then maybe another little piece
of north south that's on the far side.
What do those do those become part of
the adjacent lots? Maybe like the Frank
Court rightway gets split in half and
each side gets a half of it. Um,
chairman through you. Yeah, the uh state
statute basically states that um if a
rideway is vacated then the adjacent
owners uh can enclose it in equal
proportions is the way the statute is
worded. So typically that's a line down
the center and they each take half of
the rideway. Um, the exception to that
is that the original dedicator of that
rideway, if then it is vacated, then it
goes back to the original dedicator as
opposed to splitting it equally between
the two owners. Um, that's some of the
question about that east west chunk. Um,
I think the city surveyor is convinced
that it was vacated in its entirety. um
that Dryquick Parkway, I mean just north
of that um or just just east of that
north lot um was also part of that
original subdivision. And then as you
can see on this map, you know, Dry Creek
Parkway took that that north half and
that entire east chunk of that block.
And so everybody just wants to be clear
about sort of where the lines are, but
essentially um those two owners to the
west would get that half of that right
away sort of, you know, incorporated
into their property, so to speak, and
then the rest of the rights of way that
were vacated would go to the adjacent
owner.
>> So So will the plan be at this point
that that'll you guys will get that
wrangled out and then uh submit a final
plant that shows what becomes of all
that?
>> Yep. that that is the plan. Um the only
difference with a plat um all
stakeholders need to sign on it. So if
we if we run the vacation separately as
recommended in the staff report um then
those two house would just become part
of their legal description and then the
lot lot two and lot one would just get a
little bit bigger um towards the west to
meet that center line. Um, you can kind
of see it on the map that that little
lot that I mentioned with the difficult
to get a hold of owner. You can see
there's a dotted line there 8 feet from
their north line and that's actually a
chunk of alley that was already vacated.
So the the northerly 8t went to that
apartment complex and that 8t that uh
Mr. Lloyd's pointing at still remains
there. So their legal description is you
know lot one block two and 8 ft of that
vacated alley. And so that then it their
legal description would expand to
include 30 feet of that adjacent Frank
Court um as vacated. Does that make
sense?
>> Yeah, that makes sense. So the next
question then this plat shows a
easement for access and drainage and
maybe something else kind of on the east
half of the north south part that's
going to be vacated. So that if that
vacation goes through as we're talking
about that land will become owned by lot
three but it will continue to contain an
easement for the owner of lot one to
have access.
>> Yeah. Chairman through you. Um it's a
little tricky to see on the map but um
there is an existing curb cut off of
Rock Springs and then a gravel uh
roadway driveway that's been built
there. Uh this owner has been
maintaining sort of all of this land
including those rights of way. Um but
just maybe coincidentally all of that
built roadway falls in the east half of
Frank Court. Um but there is also
overhead power lines there adjacent to
that that run past this serve this
property but then run past it and and to
Dry Creek and across Dry Creek. So, um
there's a access and utility easement
across lot three for that owner of lot
one to get to their property. Um and
then an utility easement uh directly to
the power company to keep those overhead
power lines in place and allow them to
leave those where they are.
>> So, the the plaque shows about that
south end of Frank Court you propose not
to vacate, right? And that's about 125
feet long. I guess my question is why
not? Why not vacate the entire length of
it?
>> Y uh chairman 3, that's an excellent
question. Uh we had looked at it several
different ways. Um had I had better luck
getting a hold of that owner, I could
have talked to him about what the best
option was there. Um because the Board
of Public Utility has sewer and water
mains in that 125 ft. I think they're
they're only about 40t long. Um, it made
sense for us to just leave that stub of
right away. Um, I think the planning
department and the engineering
department aren't particularly fans of
leaving this little stub street. Um,
which is why, you know, we're amendable
to that condition to just vacate that
independently, not needing his
signature, and then BOPU can decide, you
know, how they want to handle putting an
easement in there. Uh my discussions
with the engineering department at BOPU
are that um they would most likely just
require that an easement be put down uh
to cover those facilities and then when
when it kind of came up or if they were
doing work in the area, they would
probably abandon those mains. Um
and then the easement would be would be
then vacated and it would just become
raw land.
I think this is the last one, but
>> that's all right.
>> So eventually
um and I guess maybe the question be at
what point, but at some point then if
this goes stays as shown with 125 ft of
Frank Court still a dedicated road, will
that have to have curb and pavement
installed on it?
chairman been through you that uh
another good question. I think that what
you will see uh before you um should
this preliminary plat be approved by the
governing body is a plat that will come
in with and all of Frank Court having
been vacated by separate instrument.
Um, if it was to remain in place,
um, I would think the way the rules are
currently written that it would have to
be constructed when any development was
proposed probably on lot three of this
plat. Um, typically the city won't say,
well, there's this deficient road and
you're not doing anything, but it should
be built to current standards. So, I
mean, the rightway's been there for
decades. Um,
and so I I don't think that anything
would be built there until something
else was proposed adjacent to it. Um,
but I think what you'll end up seeing is
that the entire Frank Court is vacated.
Um, at those owners will those ownership
lines will move out and as you noted
earlier, lot three doesn't actually gain
any usable land. It's all easement, but
um, it just kind of cleans things up and
it's no longer public roadway. It's
just, you know, private private access
and utilities.
So to clarify in my mind, if if all this
works, we're going to wind up with a a
city lot, lot one that is not connected
to a city roadway except for a potential
easement. Correct.
That is correct. Okay.
And I don't know if city attorney was I
wish I was better at this, but and I as
I understand it, all three of these are
owned by the same person right now,
>> right?
And if I remember my rules correctly, if
if you've got two lots and they're one
is served by an easement when
when the easement
serving the dominant lot,
I guess when the dominant lot is owned
by the servant lot,
it extinguishes the ement. So once we do
this, if we're relying on an easement,
maybe I'm wrong here, but that easement
ceases to exist unless it's an easement
to benefit
something like the public.
Um, yeah, chairman, uh, you sound like
an attorney,
uh, nearly by accident. So, uh, you're
right in terms of case law and and
almost, you know, every easement created
by separate instrument that there's
there's lots of precedent for those not
being enforced because you can't grant
an easement to yourself.
Um, this can be thought of maybe
contextually more like um
I mean, one example that comes to mind
is the apartments at SweetGrass.
Um, I don't know if any of you are
familiar with that project, but there's
29 apartment buildings and they all
share access through a common lot. So,
they, you know, they they get in and out
of the adjoining roadways where they're
addressed by
virtually basically an easement, right?
It says this this lot is an easement for
them to get in and out. Um, and it it
would serve the same here that basically
it's a sort of considered a complex of
buildings and maybe there's 20 buildings
on lot three, right? But um they can use
use that easement to serve both
properties and they will both be
addressed off of Rock Springs. Um and
since the easement is created by a plat,
it exists no matter what. It says
whoever owns this lot can go back and
forth to this other through this other
lot um by right. And so it's not between
indiv I mean this this comes up on plats
often, right? because usually you have a
single person creating a plat where the
long-term intent is to separate out the
properties and so when you when you plat
an easement uh like that the I think the
underlying assumption is that there will
be separate ownership at some point and
so the the corridor is established by
the recorded document uh independently
of grantees. Does that make sense?
somewhat in my mind the easement still
would need to come into existence at at
the time. You have a separation of
ownership which kind of leaves would
leave it in limbo here. And I
>> and I'm not entirely certain what is
gained from a planning perspective by
creating a lot that's a city lot that's
not connected to the city roadways.
Chair, I I mean I I do understand your
concern. Um I think on this particular
question of the easement, um I could I
could dig up many many examples, some in
the county. So, if you'd be interested
in either talking offline or or having
me share some of those with the staff um
as examples of how this has been done
before, I could do that. Um and I think,
you know, in this case, like I said,
it's just kind of messy. Neither of
these streets is ever going to be
extended across Dry Creek, right? I
mean, it's you can see the flood plane
there on the boundary. That's a city
park. Uh there's already developed lands
on the other side where these roads
won't connect. And so what you have
currently is this, you know,
citymaintained right ofway, open to the
public, um it's been maintained by a
private owner um for, you know, half a
century. And so uh it is a unique
scenario but um it does not make sense I
think in my mind and and as far as I
understand in in staff's mind to leave
these public rights of way that are
deficient and privately maintained and
it's it's more of a liability to the
city to leave them public right away
than to you know create like I said a
complex of buildings that are addressed
off Rock Springs Street. So, uh, it's a
legitimate question. Um,
I mean, I could talk to other attorneys
about it. I I think I can totally see
the, um, the gears turning on on case
law and how does this work and, uh, and
the questions about easements. I'm
pretty familiar with a lot of that
stuff. But, um, I think in this case, it
this is just this stranded property
that's been there for for quite some
time. and um the owner is just trying to
kind of clean it up and say, "Look, if
I'm going to be maintaining this and
you know, I I might as well have it be
under my ownership." And the city's kind
of saying, "Well, yeah, why why do we
have a public road here that technically
we're supposed to be maintaining when
it's built deficient and it doesn't
serve anything other than this, you
know, one or two people?" So, um I think
I think they're valid questions. I
typically um
I think that's part of what makes my job
interesting is that you run into these
things all the time and it's like okay
here's what is on the ground and how do
we how do we solve it as best as we can
um with the tools we have
>> and I think part of the question is is
what becomes of lot three and I know
there's not a firm plan in place
but if I were going to get have somebody
give me a hint on if I were a betting
man and somebody were going give me a
hint on what I was going to bet lot
three would be. What would be the best
guess?
>> Um, yeah, I think if I was going to put
something out there, um, it would be a a
cold sack. So, I, you know, we had we
had been approached by this owner to
say, "What if this lot developed and how
would it develop?" We do have an example
of that that um that wasn't shared, but
they I'm I'm not lying to you when I say
they don't have any intent to develop
it. they were curious as to how it could
be developed. Um, but the person that
sold it to them had also had somebody
else do the same thing. And um, they're
remarkably similar. So, there's a
manhole, if you can see, Hope Court,
kind of sticks right out of the bottom
there off of Rock Springs, and there's a
manhole right there in the middle of the
road. And so, uh, both myself and this
other, um, consultant said, "Well, the
best thing to do would be to put a main
straight out of that manhole, straight
up lot three, and put smaller houses on
either side of it, um, and serve them
all off of that. And then in terms of
serving lot one, then we looked at um
both access andor utility services, you
know, kind of cutting through lot three
or potentially coming down the the to be
vacated Frank Court. So, I mean, we
we've looked at this a few different
ways. Um I think that would be the most
logical way that someone would develop
it, but given the the shape of the
property and the and the size of it,
it's it's rather difficult to develop.
Um, depending on the size of the home
you wanted to put on there,
it could potentially be a multif family
lot, too, where you build a couple
apartment buildings. Um, or one small
apartment building.
>> Thank you. That's kind of what I was
wondering about and what that look like.
>> I think it would be and and whether
a right of way would need to be
maintained in order to give access past
Department apartment block. Any other
questions from staff?
Yeah. I'm sorry. Any other questions
from the commission
for the applicant?
Okay. Staff report, please.
Mr. Chair, members of the planning
commission, my name is Seth Lloyd. I'm
with the planning and development
department for the city of Cheyenne. Um
once again, um
on behalf of Connor White, I'll
presenting staff report on this project.
Um the proposed plat in front of you is
a a replat of a previously platted area
to create three lots from existing land
and streets. Um as the applicant
mentioned, um well, we'll we'll start
off with some background other
background here. Um the land is
currently zoned um um is currently under
the urban land use urban residential
land use future land use designation by
plan Cheyenne which anticipates
residential development and also is
zoned MR in city limits which
anticipates medium density residential
development. The property is currently
developed with two houses and um as the
applicant mentioned, we have a lot of
historical problems with this property.
Um not really created by the applicant,
not really a a concern with where this
project wants to go. It's more concerns
with where this project has been. Um so
the the plat in of itself, the end
result that the applicant is shooting
for is fairly straightforward. However,
there's a lot of background problems
with this area. Um, one is the previous
vacation of East West Frank Court, um,
which appears to have been vacated by
the county in, uh, the late 80s. Um,
however, was never recorded and never,
as far as I can tell, that was never
transferred um, ownership from that
time. Um, I believe the item is on the
agenda of the county commissioners
tomorrow if that's something you're
interested in. um to discuss this
vacation. Um that still might render
some ownership uh issues uh within this
plat boundary because I don't know if
that means it goes to the owners of the
1980s or it goes to the owners of today.
Um so we need to clarify that ownership
issue before we can actually do a final
plat for this land. However, since the
preliminary plat is pretty
straightforward as to what we want to
accomplish, um that's more of a
condition on the preliminary plat
approval and we'll come forward with a
final plat once that issue has been
resolved. Similarly, North South Frank
Court is was proposed initially to be
partially vacated by this action,
leaving a narrow substandard street
width. Um the applicant did submit to us
a revised preliminary plat kind of
showing um more of Frank Court vacated
which would be more appropriate.
However, staff's recommendation is just
go ahead and vacate the entirety of
Frank Court all the way down to Rock
Springs Street um uh as the applicant
mentioned the owner to the southwest
right at the intersection of Rock
Springs and Frank Court um has some sort
of development that has uh encroached
into that rightway. it would make sense
for them to go ahead and obtain that
right of way and make it part of their
property as opposed to them um being in
the right of way. Um and it's also
staff's understanding that the lack of
signatures on a cleanup plat for this is
more about it's not urgent for the
property owners to the west um than it
is truly an objection to the project. Um
we have not as staff heard any
objections to the project uh uh at this
time. However, um once again, we we will
need to go through the plinary plat
process. Another advantage of the
plinary plat process is if it's approved
by the governing body that gives staff
the direction to initiate do a city
initiated vacation of Frank Court um
where the city initiates the vacation of
Frank Court. Um the city can initiate
vacation of any street in the city
without um owner signoff. And um as the
applicant has already mentioned, this
Frank Court is not developed as a city
street. really doesn't serve as a city
street. Basically serves as a driveway
to one or two property owners. Um mostly
just one property owner who to be fair
has been also maintaining it um for the
most part. Um that it appears this
original subdivision that established
these streets way back in the day was
done in the county and they probably
were required to maintain based on
county subdivision regulations. Um but
since that time the city's expanded out
in the area and very recently actually
the city annexed the last pieces of this
area with part of a county pocket
annexation. Um so this has been a
project that's had a lot of issues um in
the background that need to be resolved
before we can final plat it but the end
result that is being requested is is
fairly straightforward. Um I would take
a couple of notes based on commissioner
questions. Um, we do have what would be
a non-conforming lot with lot one
proposed with this project. Um, due to
the fact that the lot is way back there
and is has no um, frontage on a public
street, that's not usually our standard.
However, this is a existing conditions
scenario. Um, we'll work with what we
have the best we can on that lot. Um,
this lot to the rear also lot one has no
access to city water or sewer um, at
this time. Um we anticipate that we need
to make sure that they can get that
access um at a later date. Hopefully
that access easement access and utility
easement will suffice. Um the
uh and then one last item that was
brought up by the commissioners
um regarding uh easements. Um it it's my
impression, although I'm not an
attorney. I'll caveat that that um it's
a little bit different when you grant an
access easement to a lot owner versus to
a lot versus granting it to a person.
And so it's not granted to the person,
it's granted to the lot. And that way
that lot has access. Um otherwise, we'd
have a lot of problems with development
actions because in order for a plat to
go forward, we have to have buildable
lots. And part of having a buildable lot
is having an accessible lot. Um, so with
the anticipation of lot one and lot
three eventually dividing in ownership,
we would need to make sure lot one has
appropriate access in order to approve a
subdivision of land. Um,
that's all the comments uh we have as
staff on this project. Um, once again,
just based on the nature of the project,
um, we don't anticipate these streets to
go anywhere. So, we're recommending an
exception to block sizes. And then we
already went over the various issues
that need to be resolved before a final
plat can be submitted. Um there's
various methods and uh ways to solve
these problems. It's just something that
needs to be solved before we can really
uh feel comfortable approving a final
plat. Um staff recommends approval with
various conditions and I'm available for
any questions.
>> Thank you commissioners. Questions for
staff?
Commissioner Connor, I can't see whether
you're shaking your head.
>> No questions.
>> Okay.
Um
I guess uh the public comment
going once, going twice, nobody on Zoom.
Public comment is closed.
uh commission
I guess. Do we have any further
clarific
clarifications or
anything? Okay,
I'll accept a a motion. I I I guess
I'm curious if there's any heartburn
about any of the staff's
con proposed conditions
from anybody.
Okay, I'll accept a motion.
Uh, chair.
>> Yes. Commissioner Wilson.
>> Uh, I move to approve the Dry Creek
Vistas preliminary plat subject to staff
recommended exception and conditions
>> and looking. Okay. Seconded by
Commissioner Lair.
Discussion. Move the commission.
>> Uh, chair.
>> Uh, Commissioner Olsen. Uh just for
staff, it would be kind of nice to have
more of an opinion from the city
attorney on that access maybe when the
final plaque comes just to or just
something of that nature to touch on
that
since we will be seeing this again
probably.
>> Something in the nature of re-education
and correction of the chair's
recollection.
>> Mr. chair for you.
>> Commissioner Lar,
>> maybe this is a point of information
from staff I should have asked earlier,
but just to clarify the
the flow of this. Now, we're if we pass
this motion approve the fi the
preliminary plat with the conditions
that have to be addressed be prior to
the preliminary to the final plat. Will
that final plat ever come back to us? Is
that just going to bypass us and go to
the city council?
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, the final plat comes back
to the planning commission.
Anything else from commission?
Well, we've got a motion and a second.
So, staff, please call roll.
Tony Leairard.
>> Hi.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> I.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Hi.
Bob Mia
>> I.
>> Lonnie Olsen
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you. Staff read item C into the
record, please.
>> Item C, PUDC-25-258,
county pocket annexation number 9,
assigned zoning.
Oh, I'm sorry. I need to call for I
guess staff will serve as agent here.
Mr. Chair, as this is a city initiated
uh application, staff will be uh agent
and staff report, I suppose, at the same
time. Um this county pocket annexation
is a city um council goal to to annex
all county pockets with that were 100%
surrounded by city limits. Um the
particular county pocket that is under
um annexation consideration is the one
north of the mall, north of Lowe's,
north of um Walmart and a couple of
county pockets a little bit to the
northeast of that area. Um this large
pocket is enclosed by Story Boulevard.
Um that's the enclosing uh nature of
that pocket. Um the annexation is not um
up for review by the planning
commission. It's the assigned zoning
that we'll be doing in coordination with
the sanctation. So the all the land
within this area is currently zoned LU
in the county land use um which allows
for a variety of uses and types of uh
developments um mostly by conditional
use processes. Um the large uh pocket
that's surrounded by Story, Converse,
Del Range, and Powderhouse. um the
remainder of that land um it's a large
amount of land. It's currently utilized
for grazing um and has a variety of
potential uses in the future. So city
staff has um assigned the zone of AG
agricultural for that zone um due to
respecting the current use of the land
and also not guiding any development
actions at this time. The two smaller
pockets um one of them is almost
completely surrounded by MR zoning. So,
city staff has assigned that pocket MR
zone and the other one is um surrounded
on uh two sides essentially by MR zoning
and on two sides essentially by NR3
zoning. Um due to the lower intensity
nature of the MR zone and also the fact
that some of the NR3 zone is across
Converse which is a major roadway um
staff felt it more appropriate to assign
the zoning of the lower intensity which
would be MR zoning for that entire
pocket. Um should an applicant wish to
uh upzone that area, they can come
through the zone change process which
would come back to planning commission
and the city council. Um that is staff's
analysis as to the appropriate assigned
zones for these pockets. Um and I'm
available for any questions
chair.
Uh, so
>> Commissioner Lson
>> staff, I understand that there's
relatively to all the other county
pockets, there's relatively few land
owners that are associated with this.
Was there any communication with those
or did you hear anything from Thank you,
Mr. Chair. Um, we have been in extensive
discussions with the land owner of the
largest pocket. Um, I should say land
owners, there's a whole family that's
essentially the land owner there. Um and
there's actually anou through council
discussing how we would treat that
pocket. Um and so they are definitely
well aware of the annexation and the ag
zoning. The believe AG zoning is
actually their preference. Um the other
land owner is a developer who usually
develops single family homes. Um so we
would anticipate that that developer
would be looking forward to having their
land all within city limits all zoned MR
um ready to be developed without any
cost to themselves.
And chair, members of the commission,
I'd like to add a couple of other
things. The school district does own a
parcel of land out there. Um, so they
have not uh commented on that. They were
mailed notice. Um, it really does not
affect them other than they'll be in the
city limits when they develop, which it
would have to be if they choose to
develop. It's a parcel generally located
to the norththeast of uh the Coyote
Ridge Elementary School and there have
been discussions with the uh
representatives of the pockets that are
on the east side of Converse which is
another developer as Mr. Lloyd had noted
um and they are aware of this annexation
occurring
and I should note that the one of the
primary concerns that the large land
holder had was continuation of their
agricultural use. Uh right now they have
an agricultural use that is active on
the property. They just wanted some
further assurances that they would be
able to continue. Um, one of the unique
things about this is when a property is
agriculture agricultural, you can have
an agricultural uh, property tax
exemption. Believe Mr. Wiga may be aware
of that. Um, with some ranching and and
agriculture in his background. Um, the
net increase in taxes I believe was just
under I think it was just under $200 for
the entirety of that acreage because all
that changed was the difference in city
mill levy. So, it was um often uh a
concern for this property owner in the
past who one of the representatives used
to frequent the planning commission
meetings like every planning commission
meeting in the past. Um he always had
concerns with with property taxes, but
we engaged uh them uh and the county
assessor to really just iron it out and
say this is where it's going to go. And
everyone kind of raised their eyes and
said, "Oh, this is good. We can move
forward.
Mr. Chair through you,
Commissioner Leair. So, I guess one of
the good things about this, it'll clean
up those issues like we had at the last
I think our last meeting um with the the
the business with the apartments on the
north side of that new Carlson extension
where we had the remainder lot that
didn't have a plan but was part of a
parcel. So, in order to keep everything
kind of conforming to parcels with in
and out of the county, we had to uh you
had to do the remainder lot. So now if
everything's in the city, they they can
pretty much slice things up the way they
want.
Yeah.
I've got a question for staff. thinking
about the
I mean I I think we're covering the
pasture
that I would imagine is going to get
grazed until it isn't. But but on the on
the east side of Converse, there's a
couple of pockets that we're assigning
zoning to and I' I've got some degree of
familiarity. They're kind of on my dog
walking route.
um
with as I understand it, we're looking
at an MR zone which would support as I
understand it forplex development but
would not support
development of the intensity of the
for lack of a better term the the low in
the subsidized housing that is is west
of Anderson east of Anderson school east
of of Converse. Correct.
>> Mr. Chair, the MR zone does not allow
any style of apartments as a use by
right. They would only be conditional
use. Um the MR zone does allow town
homes, large size town homes, duplexes,
and single family homes. Um so,
>> okay.
>> Any any development of those two pockets
with something more intense than large
town homes would require either a zone
change or a conditional use approval.
>> Okay. Thank you. And as a followup, I
believe we
recently approved a zoning and perhaps
even a plat for something like patio
homes or something like that through
there.
uh would that be permitted under the MR
zone or or are we inviting
something that are we imposing a zone
that would be dissimilar from
what is immediately adjacent or at least
currently platted and proved to be
immediately adjacent to these
Mr. chair. Um the MR zone does not allow
the patio homes cottage lot style
development as a use by right. It would
be reconditional use approval and any
subdivision of land out here would
obviously have to go through um I I
should say any subdivision of land um
for patio homes or similar types of
development even single family homes in
the MR zone would require um coming
through the planning commission and the
city council um because they would be
dedicating streets and platting more
than a couple of lots in that process.
So, um the MR zone would um at this
stage there would almost certainly have
to be some sort of subsequent public
process to develop th those pockets.
Okay. And last question, I know we're
not dealing with the annexation here.
Did we already
annex and zone the land north of Wild
Bluff, south of Story Boulevard,
east of Point Bluff?
There's kind of a block in there that
I know it to be wide open and
kind of ridgy or something that does not
appear to be included in this. Is there
is there a reason that it's not included
in this?
>> Mi Mr. Chair, any of the land south of
Story Boulevard not highlighted has
previously been annexed.
>> Okay, that's what I wanted clarification
on. Thank you.
So, as a followup clarify, we can expect
not to see any additional
annexation assigned zoning after this
for land south of Story Boulevard, east
of Converse, west of Ridge or whatever.
Um, Mr. Chair, in this area, um, this is
the second to last county pocket
annexation. So you will see one more
county pocket annexation, but it will be
um clean up to the west and far south
areas of Cheyenne. So no other county
pocket annexations will be in this area.
Um and we we would have to go quite a
ways to the east to start getting more
annexations south of Story Boulevard.
Okay. So we don't have any other county
pockets to worry about. Okay. Not in
that area. Okay. Thank you.
Uh commission. Any other questions for
staff?
Public comment.
I'll open this up for public comment.
Going once. Going twice. Nothing on
Zoom.
Public comment is closed. And I'm
looking for a motion
from the commission.
Chair Commissioner Wilson. Uh,
I move to recommend the governing body
approve the assigned zoning for land
south of Story Boulevard, east of Powder
House Road, north of Del Range
Boulevard, and west of Ridge Road to AG
agricultural and MR medium density
residential as shown in the attached
zone change map, noting that the project
meets review criteria for approval.
>> Do I have a second?
>> Second.
Seconded by Commissioner Hernandez.
Any discussion of the motion debate
proposed amendments to the motion from
the commission
hearing? None. Will staff please call
roll.
>> Bob Matia.
>> I.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Tony Larard.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Hi. Lonnie Olsen.
>> I,
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you. And will staff please read
the final item into the record.
>> Item D, PLTA-25-10,
Accessory Dwelling Unit, ADU, text
amendment.
>> Staff, please provide the report.
>> Mr. Chair, Seth Lloyd with the City of
Cheyenne Planning and Development
Department. Um this proposal proposes
amending um portions of the unified
development code in respect to accessory
dwelling units or ADUs. Um just for the
information of the commission or for any
members of the public who may not be
aware of what an ADU is, an accessory
dwelling unit is a second unit on the
same property as a principal dwelling
unit that can take many forms. Um
sometimes it's an detached unit all by
itself. Um, sometimes it's attached to
the house, sometimes it's in a garage,
sometimes it's in the principal building
above a garage or in the principal
building in a basement. Um, just there's
a lot of different ways, um, this could
be done, but the essential fact of the
matter is it's two dwelling units on one
property. Um, our current ADU code
requirements, um, they exist in the ad
in the, um, unified development code
right now. Um, ADUs are allowed as an
administrative use in all of our normal
residential zones. Um and a they are
limited to only one per lot. Um either
and the property owner must live in
either the principal building or the
ADU. Um the size is limited to 40% of
the principal building. Um or if it's in
the basement, it can be the same size as
the principal dwelling unit. Um they are
required to generally maintain the
neighborhood character and they are
required to provide one additional off-
streetet parking space.
Um the proposed amendment would strike
the requirement for a property owner to
live on the property and it would strike
that the additional parking space must
be off off streetet. Um our unified
development code has a lot when it comes
to on street parking um uh allowances.
So, a a commercial business or an
apartment complex can meet some of their
parking requirements by providing
parking on the street um or credit some
of their parking requirements by parking
on the street. Um this would just allow
for some more flexibility when it comes
to accessory dwelling units. Um also, um
the phraseology in the code right now
says it has to be on a discrete portion
of the lot, but by doing this, you could
have a third stall on your driveway, for
example. It wouldn't have to be behind
the house or hidden or something like
that. So it just gives some more
flexibility for the parking. Also, when
it comes to accessory dwelling unit
owner occupancy, um the national trends
um discourage that as a poison pill
toward accessory dwelling units um as it
were. Um it limits the number and um
ability to do accessory dwelling units.
And at the end of the day, um, the
population, the traffic, the noise, the
differences between that between an
owner occupied ADU and a notowner
occupied ADU are fairly minimal.
Um, with this code amendment, um, there
would be some conforming amendments to
our code. Um, right now, our code does
call a flat overflat duplex differently
than an ADU. Um, however, once we have
an ADU
not being required to be owner occupant
occupied, the difference between a flat
or flat duplex and an ADU is minimal to
nothing really. Um, I did talk to
building departments in Montana where
they are required to have ADUs without
and they're required to not require
the state does not allow municipalities
to require own occupancy for those ADUs.
So, I talked to cities of similar size
to Cheyenne in Montana and their
building department treats an ADU the
same as they would a flat or a flat
duplex. There's no no differences. Um
whereas our current building official
has has given some more lenuency in
building code. Um considering kind of a
single family home as long as the owner
is there. Um that would be taken away.
So that is kind of a little bit of a
trade-off here is that by removing the
owner occupancy now all ADUs are
duplexes. But also by doing that um
staff proposes to um put all flat over
flat duplexes into uh the ADU section
because there is some ambiguity in our
code as to how to treat flat or flat
duplexes. Um our duplex lot type in the
UDC really only considers sideby-side
duplexes and therefore does frontage and
used to do lot area and does setbacks
and all these things kind of based off a
sidebyside model. doesn't give staff
good direction as to what to do with a
flat over flat model. By making all
single uh sorry semi- detached dwellings
side by side and then making all flat or
flats uh accessory dwellings that gives
staff clarity into it as to enforcement
and as to what regulations apply to
which type of unit. Um
we have received uh multiple letters um
supporting this text amendment. um one
of which I believe made it into your
packet ahead of time. Others have come
in since that time. I do have I don't
know what ones you've received, so I
have printed out a couple of copies. Um
one from the Affordable Housing Task
Force, one from um the uh
Southwest Wyoming Builders Association,
Southeast, sorry, Southeast Wyoming
Builders Association. and um another
from I I the Larmy County Community
Partnership or LCCP. So, I have multiple
letters um of support. Hopefully, you've
seen them either in your email or with
the staff report. Most of them come with
similar recommendation, similar
commentary. Um so, it it's if you've
seen one, you've probably seen something
similar to the other three. Not exactly
the same. There are differences between
them, but generally all of them have
expressed support. Um, staff did review
our ADU applications that we've received
and we couldn't find any pattern as far
as like a builder who specializes in
ADUs who may be upset about the
potential change to codes. Um, so we
didn't find anybody to notify with that
potential change and if that was going
to be a concern. Um, essentially most
builders say, "Hey, owner, you want to
do this? This is what you're going to
have to do in order to have an ADU on
your property." Um, so with that, I'm
available. Um, well, obviously I should
say staff recommends approval of this
text amendment. Um, and with that, I'm
available for any questions.
Okay, I'm going to ask a real quick
question first before I turn it over to
the rest of the commission.
If we are converting the the flat
overflat duplex into an ADU
regulatory framework
and and I'm I'm envisioning that what
we're calling flat over flat is the
classic somebody's got a house and they
rent out the basement or something.
What new requirements are going to show
up
for somebody that's doing that, whether
they're officially or unofficially that
what what are going to be the new
requirements by
by placing that under the ADU framework
that would not exist prior to if we
adopt this. So Mr. share through you. Um
the by moving flat or flat duplex from
semi- detached dwelling into the
accessory dwelling um the new regulatory
framework would mean that the there
would be no requirement to meet the lot
type standards of a duplex. Um so the
new regulatory framework for those right
now for example we have this happen all
the time in in our in our um in our
staff. If we have someone who wants to
convert a single family home into two
units, flat over flat usually, um, and
they come in and they say, "Hey, can I
do this?" And we say, "Well, do you have
80 ft of frontage?" Because a
sideby-side duplex, each half of the
duplex needs 40 ft of frontage. And so
if a property owner has uh, well, I
guess it's this I use SD1. There's
actually smaller versions in in Barry
own districts, so we could do a smaller
version. But the point is they have to
have a minimum frontage in order to make
two units. So right now um in the MR
zone I'd have to have something like 60
ft of frontage to make the smallest
level of duplex to make a flat or a flat
duplex. So if I have 55 ft of frontage I
cannot do a duplex. I can only do an ADU
and then I'd have to have one of the two
be owner occupied. Whereas if I had 63
ft of frontage I can do a flatware or
flat duplex and neither one has to be
owner occupied. um by moving the flat or
flat duplex into the ADU category. Now
it won't matter if I have 55 ft of
frontage, it is an ADU instead of a
duplex and therefore I don't have to
meet that frontage requirement. Um so
this actually is
it would make it easier for property
owners who want to convert a single
family home into a duplex into a flat or
flat duplex.
>> Okay, that that explains how it makes it
easier. I'm curious what kind of the
tradeoff here. There's there's got to be
a trade-off,
>> m Mr. Chair, the flat the flatware flat
duplex already, if you're doing a duplex
under building code has the same
requirements as the ADUs will have. So
there will be no increase in regulation
from that switch.
and chair and Charles Bloom playing and
development director. I just like to add
from a building code standpoint, the way
our building official looks at this is
if you are a homeowner and you are
creating an ADU for either a relative
like a grandmother, a sister, sibling,
child that hasn't left the house yet and
you're putting that second kitchen.
Since they're all the same family unit,
they have different building codes. So
what happens is you can put in a
basement apartment that has a kitchen,
bathroom, separate entry. However, since
there's that familiar relationship, you
then don't have to build to building
codes. Well, eventually hopefully those
kids leave.
Hopefully grandma and grandpa leave, mom
and dad, whatever. Hopefully someone
leaves and you don't have that situation
going on forever. So now everyone leaves
the house. Now, a realtor picks it up
and says, "All right, I'm going to sell
this wonderful 2-unit." Um, an investor
comes by and says, "Wow, we got a
2-unit. Now, you have a 2-unit that was
lawfully permitted as an ADU. It's
manifest as two units. However, it does
not meet building code, and you'd have
to have the owner occupation."
All of these ADUs, most all of them that
are built for a family to this reduced
code, they become a problem in the
future. It happens. So, what this does,
it treats them all the same. It treats
them as what they will look like in the
end. It removes the discussion of do
they have family living there, which
changes the way um that they're
constructed.
It'll make our jobs easier hopefully.
>> So, Mr. Chair, there's two things going
on. One is flat overflat duplex is no
longer considered semi- detached
dwelling. For flat overflat duplexes,
nothing changes from building code and
zoning code makes it easier to get a
flat over flat duplex by moving it to
the ADU. The second change that is
happening is we're removing owner
occupancy as a requirement for an ADU.
That makes it slightly more difficult to
make an ADU because you know you now you
have to meet the same standards for as
you would for duplex construction for
your ADU. Um and as I said that's what
most communities where whenever there's
no longer an owner occupancy requirement
for an ADU, that's how all these
communities already treat ADUs. So,
we're we're we've been giving a little
bit of a pass to ADUs in the past that
will no longer be available because we
will remove the owner occupancy
requirement. However, the trade-off will
be a lot hopefully a lot more ADUs are
available because more people can do
that conversion if that's what their
choice is.
And to clarify, it will become more
difficult to do the conversion for
the young adult child, the grandparent
who or whoever in the first instance.
Mr. Chair, it will become slightly more
difficult for a person who is an owner
occupancy situation to create their ADU
because that now that ADU would have to
meet requirements. However, should that
owner ever move out, they can legally
sell it as a two-unit dwelling, whereas
right now they can't, even though most
realtors would say that it is.
>> Other members of the commission
questions, comments? Commissioner
Olsson?
>> Uh, chair, I have two. Uh, just to kind
of piggyback off this one, just I'm a
little bit familiar with it. So the new
requirements and I think just for
thatification of the board that would be
like fire separation and access with
windows in the basement that typically
would be required if it would be a
family occupancy one correct Mr. shares
uh through you. Um some of the new
requirements would be fire separation
between the units. Um both units would
have to have access to um certain
utility shut offs. Um and I believe both
units would have to have access to
heating controls. Um so if the upstairs
person is gone, the downstairs person
can still turn on the heat when it gets
cold. Something like that. Those are
some of the elements that will will be
required now that aren't currently
required because of the familial
relationship situation.
>> May I ask a followup to that? So to
clarify, this also means that there will
need to be separate utility metering and
everything for the ADU.
>> Mr. Chair, my understanding is that
separate meters are not required. That
is an option that someone could do, but
I it's my understanding that those would
not be required.
So my other question which is a little
little bit different is uh how many
times after a ADU is constructed do you
see that change hands and do the new
owners come into the office? Do you see
new owners do that or do they just say
great I have an ADU and
Mr. Sure. We have had one owner come in
after an owner occupancy ADU was
approved. They came in and re-uped it as
a new owner occupied ADU. That has
happened once um in the 10 years I've
been here.
And chair, members of the commission,
when an ADU is approved today, there is
a document that's recorded against the
property that says this is approved ADU.
So that will show up during someone's
title search when they when they convey
the property. So that one person they
sold it, their prospective buyer went
and make sure that the ADU was still
approved. So they had to go through and
get that transferred uh through
documentation. Our department um we
haven't tracked what's happened with the
other ones we've approved. I'm not aware
of we've gone to see if the same owners
are there. Um sounds like a great job
for an intern, but we we don't we don't
have any interns right now, but we have
not tracked it. But it's a great idea.
I'd kind of like to to see what's
happened to them. Have they just been
illegally marketed as a as a two-unit or
are they still being used? We don't
know.
>> Mr. Cher, you
>> So all these properties AUD AUDs, are
there going to be these are investment
properties then? So when you purch So
when someone's out to purchase, they're
purchasing an investment property or can
they still be owner occupied
and purchased as a single family?
>> Mr. Chair, the under the new proposed
ADU regulations, an ADU can still be
owner occupied. That there's nothing
prohibiting owner occupancy from an ADU
scenario. However, it means that all
ADUs established subsequent to this can
be marketed either as hey, you've got an
ADU that you can put your grandma in, or
hey, you've got two units that you can
just rent out both of them.
>> Other commissioners, Commissioner Lair,
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Um, this is
maybe a little bit more backing up big
picture wise. I recall an item and I
can't recall if it was when I was on the
board of adjustment or early days of the
planning commission. Uh, we had a ADU
request for a property on East Fifth
Street kind of near the airport terminal
sort of west end of the East Ridge
subdivision I think and they wanted to
put a manufactured home on a foundation
there. Uh I presume this doesn't now
allow I can't even remember what the
issue was if it was a variance setback
type problem or but it's something to do
with the fact that it was a manufactured
home.
So Mr. Chair um through you this does
not change any code requirements around
manufactured housing or um modular
housing um or IRC housing or those types
of items. So any ADU would still have to
be constructed to appropriate standards,
whether that's IRC um or whether that's
uh the zoning requirements surrounding
manufacturer housing. So um this
proposal does not propose changing any
of those. We did have a project come
through planning commission a while ago
to try and allow singlewide um
manufactured homes on platted
properties. That failed at the city
council. So that's not part of this
change. Um if if someone wants to do an
ADU, they're going to have to build it
through the appropriate zoning or or
building code standards.
>> And chair, members of the board, the
specific uh case that board member
Leairard is commission member Lair is
mentioning is that a person wanted to
place a 16 foot wide HUD manufactured
home on a lot under our present unified
development code. If you want to place a
HUD home on a lot, it must be 24 feet
wide. So, they're seeking a variance to
reduce the minimum width from 24 to 16.
Um, that was the specifics there. We
responded with a text amendment request
and that uh had approval through the
planning commission. It was ultimately
denied by the governing body. Now, the
ironic thing is is you can build an IRC
or residential code home that looks just
like a HUD home that you will not even
know the difference. that's 16 ft wide
in that neighborhood on the exact same
foundation. So, it really is just uh
three letters, HUD versus IRC that was
discussed.
>> We'll probably bring that up at our um
annual review again for fun.
>> Just just one more even more big picture
question. Are you guys are you currently
looking or considering uh other changes
uh to the ADU things to help increase
housing availability?
>> Mr. Chair, um we have been in long
discussions about loosening up the
requirements for multif family in terms
of use by right and maybe adding some
design standards or or performance
standards. So there's buffering or
something from single family homes. Um
you may have remembered from your time
on the board of adjustment, but we do
get a lot of conditional uses for multif
family on the board of adjustment and
sometimes they're little forplexes and
we have a lot of people that are are
against those just because you say the
word apartment and they think the giant
50 unit apartment building I think. Um
so there's been a lot of discussion
around that. that's going to be brought
up at the annual review as to whether or
not the governing body would want to
pursue that. Um, so there may be other
housing amendments also that may come
forward or may not. Um, there's
definitely other recommendations out
there from a national perspective about
loosening up zoning code requirements
for housing. The question is does do
they work for Cheyenne? Would our
governing body pass them? If the
governing body passed them, would the
community be in an uproar about it? So,
there's still plenty of options that we
can put forward. You may or may not see
some depending on how the governing body
reacts at the end of review.
Anything else from the commission?
Commissioner Connor and Zoomland.
>> No questions, Mr. Chairman.
>> Okay. And if the commission will indulge
me, I'd like to actually get into a
little bit of word smithing here. Um,
looking at uh the red line, it's on page
three of the six-page PDF in the section
1.4.4.
Um, just
that one of the things that is not
touched in the in the paragraph on
semi-attached dwellings, the duplexes,
there's a phrase matching the appearance
of a house
um that's still there. What what
situation is that language even supposed
to capture
in that and why does it exist and why
can't we why can't that red line extend
backward to it?
>> Mr. Chair, uh members of the planning
commission, um the original intent of
the UDC was to loop in some form-based
code type language and you will find
some duplexes are very obviously
duplexes. you can tell that there's two
separate units or that it's basically
here's one unit, here's the other unit.
Other duplexes, you might not notice
until you take a close look and see that
there's two front doors. Usually that
happens on some older duplexes with
older type construction. Um, so I think
that the objective of the original
framers of the UDC who wrote that
phraseology um were hoping that maybe we
could get some duplexes that kind of
looked like one house, just happened to
have two front doors. Um, I'm not uh I
I'm I'm not um super uh married to that
language, for lack of a better term. I'm
not I'm not overly concerned about that.
But I thought I'd leave it in because it
seemed to match what the original
framers of the UDC wanted. But if if we
need to word smith that and take some of
that language out, I don't have any
problem with that.
>> Okay. And the other place I kind of I
think I want to
>> Mr. Chair, before before you leave that
one, can I just follow up while we have
that train of thought going? But I just
I just wanted to point out that uh
paragraph or sentence you're talking
about has added red language at the very
end of the sentence or townhouse. So it
would read matching the appearance of a
house or townhouse in the final form.
>> Yes. and I was trying to wrestle and
understanding where the period was
there. And then the other place I'd like
to kind of hear hear some feedback on
before the commission
votes or or makes a motion and votes.
Um, in the in the accessory dwelling in
the red language,
there's kind of a litany in there. The
accessory dwelling may take the form of
a standalone unit in an in an accessory
building, a small unit added onto the
principal building, or a quote flat
overflat duplex.
Um,
is that an exhaustive list of the forms
in which the the ADU can can appear or
is that supposed to be three examples?
Is that
what what's the intent there,
>> Mr. Chair? Um, members of the planning
commission, that's intended to be
examples. Um, that's why it uses the
word may take the form as opposed to
shall take the form. Um, but if there's
other language that the planning
commission wants to suggest to clarify
that, I'd be open to that.
And and now I'm going to have to really
work on that because I I know the way
that it's not just shall, but the way
that it's set up, it it looks to me like
it can take one of these
three forms.
Um,
and I wouldn't be afraid to argue that
if it came down to litigation and and
and that would be that would be the type
of thing that could get litigated.
Um, Mr. Chair,
>> if I might add a
>> a small comment that might help your
wrestling with the language.
I'm thinking language in terms of
sometimes you see something that says
limited but not necessarily confined to
or not include but not necessarily be
limited to something like that to make
it more clear that there may there are
other possibilities allowed.
>> Okay, thank you. That could do it. And I
was wondering if if something along the
lines of the accessory dwelling uh may
take the take a form such as that of a
standalone unit in an apartment
building, a small unit added onto a the
principal building or a flat or a flat
overflat duplex and and make it clear
that there are examples. Either way, if
if that is the intent that these are
just examples of that could include
other unnamed forms,
I think I think the language needs
tweaked a little bit. Otherwise, I think
that they look like
it can be in one of these three forms.
Even with may take the look. I I think
it I think as worded it looks like it's
may take one of these three forms.
>> Mr. Chair, that sounds acceptable. So,
if you want to add that onto the motion
to include the term such as somewhere in
that sentence or um including but not
limited to um some language like that,
we can definitely add that in prior to
submitting to council.
and chair, members of the board, I just
wanted to note that this is included in
the staff report that um this was a
council person initiated uh text
amendment. So, we really narrowed it
down to evaluating the request of that
council member. Um so, they'll get your
recommendation and we'll note that
that's a change from the initial
ordinance and um I believe this council
person will not have any concern with
the discussion that's going on here. Any
other questions or comments for staff?
I think we need to open it up for public
comment.
Please come to the podium and state your
name and address and affiliation.
>> Uh good evening, Mr. Chair, members of
the commission. Uh Dan Dorsch, executive
director for Habitat for Humanity of
Laramie County. I ever reside at 2207
Van Landon Avenue. Um I'm here today to
just uh lend support for this amendment.
Um also um the the letters Mr. Lloyd
referenced earlier, you should have
received one from Habitat as well, but
also I do uh co-chair the Laramie County
Community Partnership Housing Action
Team and this is something we support as
well for all the reasons put forth.
thought I'd also just mention that um
the Wyoming community development assoc
uh authorities uh strategic housing plan
also mentions these types of amendments
on a local on on a local level to help
facilitate more housing being built. So
this is the reasons why we support this
and I'd say thank you for your
consideration and I stand for any
questions
commission. Any questions for the
speaker?
>> Thank you and thank you for your work.
Any other
public comment? Going once. Going twice.
Anything in Zoomland?
Public comment is closed.
Oh, I'd like to start with a motion.
Please,
>> chair.
Uh, I move to recommend the governing
body approve text amendments to the
unified development code 5.7.3
accessory dwelling units and 1.4.4
descriptions of uses of land and
buildings as outlined in this staff
report and recommended by staff. Noting
them a noting the amendments meet the
review criteria of UDC 2.4.1.D
D
uh with the following
conditions added to
or following text added to 1.4.4
semi-attached dwelling
or excuse me accessory dwelling
and adding such as as suggested by uh
chair Wigum to that section
staff. Does that follow?
>> Chair, can you state what your
suggestion was for the record?
>> Okay, that means I get to try again.
>> This is so much easier for me. Did I
hear that? Okay. Okay. Um, under one
1.4.4 four under the second paragraph in
the staff report accessory dwelling. The
final sentence uh
kind of a tweaked version
uh was the accessory dwelling may take
may take a form
such as the form of a standalone unit in
an accessory building. A small unit
added onto the principal building
building or a flat overflat duplex.
Does that capture
>> the motion? Okay, I've got a motion
looking for second. Okay, seconded by
Commissioner Leair.
Uh further discussion from the
commission comments
any any added amendments to the motion
hearing? None.
>> Mr. Chair, I just wanted to make sure
you
>> you didn't want did you also do you also
think perhaps we should make a change to
that first
um red thing you talked about in this
under semi-attented dwelling section
where it's got the appearance of a
house.
satisfied that that's
okay as written.
>> Um, Commissioner Lair, I'm not wetted
anything. I saw it and it seemed like
something could be done, but I I don't
know what the sense of the commission
is.
I I'm satisfied, I guess, with the way
it the way it reads.
>> I'd invited a comment from Commissioner
Honor. this sounds like something that
she would care about.
Hearing none.
>> Um, I'm looking at it, Mr. Chairman, but
I I don't have anything on on off the
top of my head.
>> Okay. Thank you.
With that,
I think staff, please call roll.
Um just as a reminder that it's staff's
recommended condition with the added
language to 1.4.4 for dwelling unit. Um
Tony Leairard
>> I
>> Amy Hernandez
>> Bob Mafia
>> I
>> Lonnie Olsen
>> Megan Connor
>> I
>> Mr. Chair that motion passes.
Okay. Thank you.
Other business or staff uh staff
announcements
chair, members of the commission, we are
closing our UDC annual review public
comment this week and it's not really
closed. It'll continue to collect
comments as the years go by. But what we
do is we will gather up all comments
that we've received by Friday and they
will be presented to the governing body
in a work session that will be held on
January 23rd. Um what we do there is we
take their pulse of how they feel about
different amendments that we've seen and
then we follow the UDC process and we
bring it forward to you all in the
middle of February at the midmon meeting
which will be on Tuesday because always
follows President's Day. Um and we'll
kind of let you know that the council
either supports it or doesn't support it
so we're not all wasting time with
different amendments. So that is
continuing to go forward. I do not
believe that we have an item for midmon
January. So as of uh unless we want to
do a planning commission 101, we could
do a training element if you wish. Um
but we can also do that in February or I
can send out the PowerPoint uh to you
all for your review. Um, so that's
really, oh, what else is going on is we
hope that by the next meeting we have an
RFP that is ready to move forward with
an update to plan Cheyenne's community
character chapter from 2014. Uh, this is
a little bit dated. It's on our website
right now. Um, this is the community
character plan which really sets
policies for what we want our zoning
code to look like. um how we want to
develop what our land use plan is going
to look like, how do we want to address
housing, how do we want to address
roadway standards and those types of
items. So, it's really the uh guiding
factors in the the the guidance as to
how our development code is is formed.
We have been doing a lot of stuff
backwards just because we understand
it's important, but we really should
have these uh principles and policies
outlined um in our planning documents to
to better support where we're moving
forward with our development
regulations. Uh once this project is out
on the street, we would expect it to
take about 18 months for completion. Uh
we do intend to have a steering
committee that will help guide this plan
through the process. We will be reaching
out to planning commission members to
see if anyone wishes to be on that
steering committee who will also have a
variety of other uh interests within the
community, possibly Mr. Dorsch behind
us. Um but or other other folks um but
it it will be an inter agency um
endeavor and should be great
and those are all the updates that I
have uh regarding the department right
now.
Okay. To clarify, we aren't going to
have a midmon meeting. Midmon chair,
members of the commission, as of right
now, there is no midmon. Uh set.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Okay. With that, do I have a motion to
adjurnn?
I would so move.
>> Okay, we're adjourned.